# **CODY GRIFFITH**

Santa Cruz, CA  $_{\circ}$  669-204-6374  $_{\circ}$  cody.griffith94@gmail.com

mathnstein.github.io



## Mathematical Research Scientist

## **Summary**

After about a decade of honing my applied mathematics I have developed the tools, experience and programming knowledge to make myself useful to any field of analysis. I am a research scientist in mass spectrometry where I specialize in developing algorithms for internal use as well as for customergrade products. My hope is to continue to broaden my skill set and work towards making a positive impact both at the industry/research level but also towards social good.

## Education

2016 - 2018 M.Sc in Applied Mathematics

University of British Columbia - Vancouver, Canada

2012 - 2016 B.Sc in Applied Mathematics

Metropolitan State University of Denver - Colorado, USA

## Work experience

December 2018 -Current Research Scientist

908 Devices - California, USA

New to the realm of mass spectrometry, I quickly learned how to build efficient algorithms for the data-rich orbit-trap mass spectrometers. I soon was tasked with anticipating potential customer use cases and participated in UI/UX design for analysis software. While building new products, I was also in charge of maintaining current device platforms and functionality while bringing new features into software updates. Along with maintenance, I gave expert analysis for in-field device data reachback. All of this together taught me important facets of business development on top of algorithm design.

May 2018 - October 2018

Research Scientist

Data Science for Social Good (UBC) - Vancouver, Canada

As a means of applying my skills that would have a maximal impact on my community, I took part in a data science initiative to help the nearby city of Surrey understand the pitfalls in addressing childhood vulnerabilities. This project lasted a summer and led to unique collaboration with Microsoft Vancouver and culminated in a paper and a platform to combine city data, public census data, and the unique Early Childhood Instrument (EDI). This platform has been since utilized by Surrey and there is a follow-up project underway to expand on our findings.

Sept. 2016 - May 2018

Research/Teaching Assistant

University of British Columbia - Vancouver, Canada

As part of my training at the Master's level, I continued developing my teaching skills while taking on grading duties, leading in class activities and proctoring exams as a teaching assistant. But as a research assistant, I learned how mathematical research was done and further developed my ability to communicate high level ideas. I had gained insight into a various selection of methods and developed new approaches and methods in my research area.

## **Projects**

- Formed the basis of analysis on a two-dimensional dynamical system with strange bifurcating behavior.
- Partnered with Data Science for Social Good to create a central database and platform to analyze this to explain childhood vulnerability in the city of Surrey.
- Used Spatial & Temporal Analysis to help Groundwork Denver to model E-Coli trends in a local river.
- Placed meritorious winner in 2016's Mathematical Competition in Modeling (MCM).
- Presented at JMM 2016 on computational and theoretical extensions to topics in Linear Algebra.
- Established a sequence of independent studies to develop a personalized and interest driven track: Functional Analysis, Discrete Wavelet Transformations, Advanced Linear Algebra, and Measure Theory.
- Developed a method of analysis on a Dual-Capacity Stochastic Queue. Then, presented this work at the 2015 MAA regional conference in Colorado Springs as well as at the Undergraduate Research Conference in Denver.

## Skills

- Extensive programming with Mathematica, R, Matlab, Python and Julia
- Intensive critical thinking and problem solving honed along with Mathematics
- Ability to manage projects and experience leading a team
- Significant use of document preparation in Latex, Markdown, Overleaf and Microsoft office
- Familiar with slide preparation via Latex (beamer) or Powerpoint
- Well versed in source control and project work (Dropbox, Github, Subversion)
- Experience with the Cloud Network and other online data storage

## Referees

#### Dr. Rachel Kuske Dr. Elizabeth Ribble Dr. Kevin Lin **Dr. Robert Green** Rachel@math.gatech.edu emcclel3@msudenver.edu kevin.lin@ubc.ca bgreen@908devices.com Chair of Mathematics Chair of Mathematics Director of DSSG Algorithms Lead Georgia Technical University MSU Denver at UBC 908 Devices Direct boss at 908 Devices. Advising professor for my data Supervisor at DSSG Master's thesis supervisor. science projects.